妮基塔
嗨 我说你这个白痴
Zap, you fucking moron, huh?
我有钥匙 你就会砸东西
If you'd just wait, I got keys to open it.
砸了它
I zapped it.
喔 砸了它
你妈生你就会砸东西，你这个白痴
"I zapped it. I zapped it." Is that all you were born for, to zap things?
这可是我自己的家
You're a real moron, you know?
真是个白痴
I grew up here.
你一定知道钱藏在哪
Great, then I bet you know where to find the stuff.
不必我们瞎找了 对吧
Then we won't waste a second, huh? Right.
一定要找到
Gotta have it.
要发财了宝贝
You'll have it, my angel.
对 你得先走了
我亲自赶过来
Yeah, well, you'd better get a move on, because I'm going down there myself.
我要他们终身后悔作贼
I'm going to make them wish they'd picked another line of work.
找到没有
You have it?
快了快了 你忍耐一下
It's coming. It's coming. Be patient!
山鸡 快呀
Coyotte! Go, moron!
你他妈昏头了
For Christ's sake!
他妈的
Shit!
到底在哪
Where is it?
嗨 混蛋 把灯关了
What's the matter with you assholes? Turn the lights off.
你们一大帮小痞子
What do you know, a whole gang of little punks.
在我的店干什么
What are you looking for besides trouble?
山鸡的老爸 是吧 啊
Coyotte's father, huh? Huh?
安托万
Antoine?
爸 爸爸
Papa?
怎么会是你
It can't be you.
我们要找点东西
We're desperate.
想杀你的儿子 老爸 啊
Gonna put a hole in your boy, Daddy, huh? Huh?
报警 我宰了你
I'll kill you!
砸啊
Do it, Zap!
有种的都来吧 老子叫瑞可
Is that all? This way! This way! My name's Rico! My name's Rico!
砸 来吧
Zap, yeah!
砸 快点砸 啊
Do it! Do it! Do it, Zap!
别留一样东西 砸 快点砸
Do it, Zap, huh? Don't miss anything, huh?
我全砸了
Go on zapping everything!
砸呀 瑞可 我全砸了
Everything, Rico! I'm zapping everything!
砸 砸呀
Zap! Zap! Zap!
杀光了
No more?
唉 不要
Shut up.
安静 通通闭嘴
Shut up, I said!
出来吧
Let's go. Let's go.
把手背到后面
Hands behind your back.
两腿撑开
Spread your legs. Spread them out!
你 什么名字
Name, full name.
妮基塔
Nikita.
我警告你小烂货
A piece of advice, sweetheart.
别演戏了
Drop the act.
别给我玩花样 我会盯死你的
You might think it's funny, but I'm on to you.
懂吗
Got it?
懂了
Got it.
要不要歇一下 警长
You might want to take a small break.
没事 我知道她这一套
She's fine. She's fine. I know her type.
她没问题 老把戏了
It's all a game.
给我支笔
Can I write it?
哎 这才乖吗
来 把你的全名写下来
Good girl. Now, write your full name, first and last, huh?
我叫妮基塔
My name is Nikita!
根据上诉法庭审讯的结果
After careful deliberation we declare the accused guilty...
被告在圣丹尼区
of having in the community of St. Denis...
涉嫌谋杀执行勤务的警官乔治斯・亨利
committed the willful murders of Georges Henri...
格雷高尔・安德森和米歇尔・泰林
Grégoire Anderson and Michel Terlin...
罪名成立
law enforcement agents killed in the line of duty.
被告减刑的申诉缺乏正当的理由
As to the question of extenuating circumstances...
予以驳回
the jury has found none in this matter.
现在本席郑重宣判，依照刑法304条的加刑法
Consequently, in accordance with article 304 of the criminal code...
特此判处被告无期徒刑
the defendant is hereby sentenced to life imprisonment.
剥夺公民权利30年
There is no question of review for parole for 30 years.
退庭
Court is adjourned.
30年啊
Thirty years.
我宰了你
I'll kill you all!
我要宰了你
放开我 放开 狗娘养的
Let me go, asshole!
放开我
Let me go!
我要宰了你
I'll kill you all!
让她离开这
Get her out of here.
先生 我求你 你无权这样做
Mister, please. You have no right.
我应该去坐牢才对
But I'm supposed to go to prison.
我要见我妈妈
We must find Mama.
我们已经通知她了
She's been informed.
难道她不愿见我最后一面吗
But isn't she supposed to be with me?
我现在想要我的妈妈
Please try. I must see Mama.
你们一定搞错了
Maybe this whole thing is a big mistake.
她会见我的 她会来找我的
She'll find me here. You'll see.
你们一定要等她来
You have to wait till I see Mama!
我要见我的妈妈 妈妈
Mama.
你早
Morning.
你叫什么名字
Tell me your name, please.
妮基塔
Nikita
很好听的名字
That's quite a pretty name.
怎么起的呢
Where does it come from?
从一首歌里
歌词都讲些什么
An old song. What are the words to that song?
先生 请问我是不是死了
Mister, just tell me. Is this God's heaven?
啊 还没有 不过有这个可能
No, but it's a possibility.
根据官方记录 你的生命终结于星期一清晨6点钟
Officially you're deceased as of Monday at 6:00.
经法医验尸 死因是自杀
The prison doctor confirmed that you committed suicide...
服安眠药自杀
by taking a massive dose of tranquilizers.
埋葬于阿佛美森公墓第7段第30号
You were buried at the cemetery at Maisons-Alfort, aisle seven, number 30.
爸爸 我爸爸
Titi. That's Titi.
我是政府秘密行动的专员
Let's just say I work for the government...
我们决定给你一个赎罪的机会
and they decided to give you a new chance to make amends.
要做什么
What's involved?
重生
A rebirth.
你要学会做各种技巧和淑女的仪态
You'll be taught reading, smiling, speaking, walking, even how to fight.
一切都从新开始
You'll be starting all over.
为什么
为国家服务
But what for? To serve the state.
如果我拒绝呢
And suppose I refuse?
回你的阿佛美森公墓
Aisle seven, number 30.
让我先睡一下再回答你好吗
Would you mind if I slept before I give you my answer?
给你一个小时
I'll give you one hour.
去死吧 死吧
Asshole!
怎么出去
门在前面
How do we get out of here? Right in front.
那些家伙干吗的
政府职员
Who are all these shitheads? Employees.
大家别动 没事别动
Nobody move! Everything's fine!
谁说没事 事大了
My ass it is! Nothing's fine!
我说没有事 大家别动 没事
It's under control.
快过来 开门  叫他们开门
开不了
Open it up. Nobody leaves.
叫他们开门
Tell them to open the door!
他们不会听我的
They won't open it.
那我叫你脑袋开花
停手 放下枪
I'll blow your head off! Just put it down.
你闹够了吧 快给我
Let go. Stop it now. Let go of me!
都别动
Hold it.
把枪给我
Now put it down.
好了
你们都回到位子上去吧 回去吧
All right, all right. Go back to your desks.
我第一个弹仓是不上弹的
I always leave the first chamber empty.
你应该安分几天了
That ought to clip your wings for a while.
你想好了没有
Have you made up your mind?
很好
That's fine.
在这里签名
Forms for you to sign.
你看我行吗
Think I can make it?
你会行的
You can make it.
我们从最基本的开始吧
I'm going to start you with a fairly easy program.
它像打字机的输入资料键盘
这上面是字母和数字
It's like a typewriter keyboard exactly. It's got letters and numbers.
再看这个 这个是鼠标 下面有个小滚轮
That's the mouse. There's a small roller underneath.
移动你的鼠标
彩显画面的箭头就会跟着你移动
When you move it there, it moves the arrow on the screen.
你按鼠标的左键就可以画图 它还可以选曲
Good. If you press it, you can make images, drawings.
你可以试一试
Try it.
哎 对对对 太快了 太快了
There you go. Easy. Too fast, too fast.
太快了 慢一点 对 慢一点
哎 不行 不行
That's too fast. Wait a minute.
把鼠标移到左上角 然后回来
Now, bring up the arrow back here, back in the corner right over here.
对 你看 回到这里来
Go on. Bring it back in the corner right here.
很好 你现在按这边
That's fine. Now, you press here.
很好玩
Very good.
再来
Again.
这些是一般常用的家伙
These are the firearms we generally use.
我们从最简单的开始
Let's start with the simplest weapon... Beretta 93R.
9厘米自动手枪 20发弹夹
Nine millimeter, Parabellum, 20-round clip.
你别小看它的威力
Never underrate a fatal weapon.
在我表明射击位置之前
Before I demonstrate the firing position...
你来熟悉一下这把枪
I want you to be familiar with this beast.
来个10米靶
Mark at ten meters.
你用过这种枪
You shot one before.
没打过纸靶
Never on paper.
八，九，十
Eight, nine, ten.
好 下一个
Keep it nice and round.
好
Okay.
该你了
我腿有伤
You're up. Let's go. My leg's bothering me.
没关系 试试你的反应
No problem. We'll just test your reflexes.
很简单
It's very simple.
好 就位
In position.
我会保持防御的
I'll maintain a defensive stance...
你来试着攻击我的头部
and you will try to hit me in the face.
下一个
Next one up.
坐吧
Sit down there.
我的小天使 看来你不怎么样
My dear girl, right now you don't really look like much.
口香糖吐掉
Chewing gum.
不过如果
你肯和我一起努力的话
But if our efforts are repeated in mutual...
上帝帮忙
and if God smiles upon us...
我们可以把你变成一个象样的女人
we will then be able to make you look like a human being...
不过一个最重要的认识就是
a step, an intermediate one, but necessary...
男人需要的 渴望的是...
before we have what's essential to a man...
女人
a woman.
你愉快吗
Are you pleased?
你认为什么是优雅呢
How about giving me your definition of grace?
我可粗得很
It would sound silly.
也许吧 你可以多一些微笑
Maybe so, then at least you should smile more.
当你来不及反应时 你就一直得保持这样
You've always got that when you can't respond.
微笑不能使你更聪明
It won't make you more intelligent...
但是可使看着你的人更愉快
but it's more enjoyable for those who have to watch.
微笑很简单 也很脆弱
And if you have it...
有时候会给你带来扭转乾坤的效果
perhaps its fragility gives my girl an advantage.
微笑吧
A smile.
自然点
A smile...
从灵魂里发出的微笑
and soon you'll have its power...
你会领悟它的威力的
as if from your very soul.
来试试假发吧
Shall we fix up the wig?
学习的如何
It's been going all right?
不如死了算了
I wish it were gone already.
你有幽默感了 小姐
We've acquired a sense of humor. That's very promising.
有没有认识朋友
我离不开玩鼠标
You friends with anybody? Yeah, I'm in real tight with my mouse.
能找个酒吧去喝一杯吗
How about a drink at a bar somewhere?
没到时候
Not just yet.
这鬼地方不放假的吗
Don't we ever get any rest in this factory?
不放
Never.
假发不错
The wig becomes you.
下星期日是我的生日
Next week I'll be 20 years old.
难道不能放我个周末假吗
What about giving me a pass for just the weekend?
可以派人跟着我
Have me followed?
你好 我正在设计一个程序
How are ya? I got a program to die for.
你来的正好
I'm glad you're here.
给你
For you.
哦 可以打开吗
May I open it?
一只白老鼠 放在盒子里
Had a mouse named Isher and I loved Isher
胆小如鼠的你 吓的汗毛直竖
Then I found a fellow who had a face like Isher did
伸直！就这样 伸直 好
Stretch! That's it. Stretch it out. Good.
现在转身向前
Now back and forward.
左腿迈出
Bring the left leg forward.
两个月了
她还是只会找麻烦
Yeah, for two months she's been nothing but trouble.
看来你失败了
You picked up a failure.
她的潜力很好
She has enormous potential.
什么潜力
What potential?
除了发脾气咬人以外
Up till now, except for temper tantrums and biting instructors...
你告诉我她还学会什么了
you tell me what she's capable of.
高手总要长期培养的
The best ones always take more training time.
也许需要好几年的时间
Six, seven years sometimes.
算了吧
Oh, come on.
给你两个星期证明她有能力
You've got two weeks for her to show any progress...
否则就只有把她结束掉
or that will be the end of her.
我认不出你是谁
But who are you? I don't know.
等等 你是...对了
Wait. Wait. You are... Yes.
为什么你拥在我怀中，亲爱的？ 你说呢？
Why are you in my arms, my darling? I don't know.
但现在太迟了
But it's too late now.
毕竟，也许它只是一个梦想
After all, maybe it's only a dream.
噢，我的爱
Oh, my love.
你进步不小啊 在乱跳乱蹦
You've made a lot of progress, mainly in dance...
和乱涂乱画方面
and also in painting.
但在其它的科目
But in all the other subjects...
你是零
nothing, zilch...
零蛋 懂吗
zero.
好 你等我一下
Wait for me.
生日快乐
For your birthday.
吹呀
Go ahead.
我们有两周来证明你值得栽培
We have two weeks to prove you're worthy, Nikita.
如果失败了 我也无法救你
After that, there's nothing more I can do for you.
你会完蛋的
Nothing at all.
你在看我的手
It's my hands you're looking at?
它们曾经很美
They were pretty once...
过去的事了
but that's the past.
你也曾经象我一样
You were like me before?
和你自己谈心吧
Let go and you'll find what pleases.
发掘女人的美和魅力
The pleasure of the feminine.
记住
And remember...
天底下两件事是没有极限的
there are only two things without limit.
女人的美
Femininity...
和追求美的
and the means to exploit it.
你不会吧 怎么 还没有弄好吗
I don't believe it. You're not ready yet?
你别太紧张了
You're too uptight, Amande. It's five to.
我最恨的就是迟到
已经五点了
If there is one thing I hate, it is being late.
你说过 等待刺激欲望
You said waiting increases desire.
快穿上
Slip this on.
你真的要迟到了
You're really going to be late.
我还要用一下电脑
I still have work to do on the computer.
不行 已经到时间了
马上
Enough already. One minute.
你真漂亮
You're very beautiful.
你来一起晚餐吗
是的
You're dining with me? Yes.
不寻常啊
今天是你的生日 23岁了
What's the occasion? It's your birthday, your 23rd.
难为你了 你还记得
What a good memory.
阿曼德 要加双筷子
Amande, we have company.
我们到外面饭馆吃饭 好吗
Perhaps you'd join me for dinner...
走吧
out.
我该去吗
Should I?
还和平常一样
The usual?
轻松点 把包放起来
You know that you can put your purse down.
表演个魔术给你看 注意了
Now look at this. A little magic.
啊 你等一下
Not just yet.
太公爵香槟 78年的
Taittinger, vintage champagne, '78.
请慢用 谢谢
Enjoy it. Thank you.
祝福你
To your future.
我打开了
May I now?
强力子弹 钛合金加重弹头
多附一个弹夹
It's loaded. The bullets are titanium and an extra clip in case you need it.
这算什么礼物
This doesn't make sense.
你后面坐着的三个人
There are three guests at a table behind you.
穿橙色衣服的女人和两个穿西装的
A woman in bright orange and two men in formal attire.
一个是保镖 另一个就是目标
要当场毙命
One is a guard. The other is a VIP. He's your target. Shot him twice.
完事以后就下楼
进男卫生间
When you're done, go downstairs to the men's room.
最后一间有一个能让女人通过的小窗
In the last booth, there's a small window through which a woman will fit.
你爬出去以后就到内院
You'll be in an inner courtyard.
然后穿过一条小巷
就到大街上
Then there's a long hallway that brings you to the street.
我们的司机就在那等你
只有二分钟
There will be a driver waiting for about two minutes.
过时不候
No more.
请等我走以后再行动
I'd like you to wait till I'm out of here.
她在那边
Hey, look down there.
艾迪
Eddy!
让开
Move over.
盯着
Stay there.
乔斯
Jos?
准备好了
I have it.
嗨 小姐 等等 你不能进去
Hey, miss! Hey! Stop! Come back here!
给我开门
Open it up.
她...这门有点问题
She's... There's a problem at the door.
哎 你干嘛
Miss...
该死的混蛋 给我把门打开
Damn it, you moron! Just let me in!
鲍伯 它被封死了
Bob, they had it bricked over.
窗子是封死的
The window was bricked over!
当然是封死的
Of course it was bricked.
你这个狗娘养的
你给我住手
You son of a bitch! Stop it!
你这个狗娘养的
好了 你给我住手 妮基塔
You son of a bitch! Stop it, Nikita!
好了 你给我住手 结束了
I hate you! It's over now! It's over.
我恨你
你自由了 你毕业了
I hate you! You get out tomorrow!
You get out tomorrow!
妈的 你应该冷静一点
Now just calm down. Damn it!
我们必须...
We have to...
你要想活着走出这个中心
就必须通过这个考验
We have to do this sort of exercise before releasing you from the center.
你今晚的表现很好 妮基塔
You've done well, Nikita.
今晚...
Tonight...
和以后的日子里
and all these years.
我会想念你的
I will miss you.
我最后一次吻你了
It's the last kiss you'll get from me.
你看她适合执行什么任务
Just what kind of mission do you have in mind for her?
一级
S1.
野心总是这么大
You're as ambitious as you ever were.
没叫你坐
Don't sit down.
现在给你个6月时间调整 要在9月份准备好待命
Six months' setup time. No more. I want her ready by September.
照我的意思你早就被处死了
Let me be very blunt. Had they left it to me, I would have let you die.
你还不如从他们中逃走
You'd better lie low.
不再另行通知 明白没有
There won't be any warnings. Is that clear?
能拿几支
最多能拿两支
How many are mine? Two maximum.
让诺 给她
Jeannot.
你叫玛利.革瑞特 从萨尔拉来的
是圣彼德医院的护士
Marie Clément from Sarlat, a nurse at the Salpétrière.
银行就在医院前面
我们每个月会把零钱汇给你
The bank's in front of the hospital, you'll receive a payment each month.
还有护照 驾驶本
还有零用钱 都在这里
Passport, driver's license, plus some money to start with.
你执行任务的代号是...
For your missions you'll go by the name...
加斯黑了
Joséphine.
祝你好运
Good luck to you.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
最可怕的过去了
The worst part's over.
空气好 光线也足 还有中央空调
Second floor, very bright, central heating...
而且马上你就可以搬进来
and the best part is it's available now.
很好
Perfect.
小姐 你赶时间
Excuse me. You in a big rush, huh?
没有 不赶
No, I'm not.
这台收银机有点问题
I hope not, because I got problems with my register.
好象在闹情绪
今天早上传送带坏了
It only works when it lights, and the belt broke down this morning.
没事 那就慢慢来吧 没关系
I have lots of time.
那好吧 你推过来慢慢算
Must be nice. Let's make a pile here. We'll go through it.
通心粉
Ravioli.
噢 再来一个通心粉
Why, more ravioli.
我比较慢 才来两天
Forgive me. I'm slow, but I've only worked here two days.
噢 还挺复杂的
But it's very complicated.
饼干一包 衬衫手染的
Crackers. You hand-painted your shirt?
没价钱 我想这小玩意值不了多少钱
What would you guess? Anyway, it can't be more than ten francs.
十法郎
Ten francs.
你下班要干嘛
What are you doing after work?
我没事
Nothing really.
那 一起吃晚饭怎么样
Want to have dinner with me?
十个法郎
Ten francs.
还没装修好呢
It's not finished.
我真的有点脸红
You know, I'm a bit embarrassed.
好象应该找个话题说
Usually I'm the one who does the asking.
你都不跟我说
可我不知道说什么
You've completely thrown me off. I don't know what to say.
我无所谓
Doesn't bother me.
我是挺没趣的
Yeah, well, it shouldn't bother you.
好吃 好吃
It's good.
我今天早上听到个笑话
Someone told a joke to me at work this morning.
我讲给你听
Want to hear it?
不？
Nope?
那好 我趁热吃饭
Yeah, well, I better eat while it's hot.
小姐 你在制造危险
You know this could be dangerous.
有多危险
What's the worst that could happen?
你马上就知道了
Left overs?
嗨 你说你做早点的 对吗
You said you'd have breakfast ready.
我烧水了
I put the kettle on.
是 早糊了
Yeah, right. Don't overdo it.
早餐 公主的早餐
The princess is served.
好吧 先把它吃了 我要上班了
All yours. Because I should go.
睡得好吗 我的公主
The princess slept all right?
好
Yeah.
请里昂他来家里吃饭怎么样
So what do you say we invite Léon for dinner?
好啊
Good.
你知道吗 他最近老想家
The guy's really been missing Britanny the past week.
我来做馅饼
I'll make us crêpes.
做馅饼？就凭你？
Make crêpes? You?
我打算跟他合伙
We might be partners soon.
做什么
我们造游艇
Doing what? We want to design boats.
你会游泳吗？里昂可是好手
You know how to swim? Léon's a good guy.
别损了 他连女人的身体都不敢碰
Yeah, but he can't find his way out of a paper bag.
你的嘴好毒啊
You're so cruel.
也请你朋友来
You might want to invite your friend. Who's that?
你不是说在服装店碰到老朋友吗
一个金发美女
You told me you met one of your friends in a boutique. A blond...
我想是上周
Last week, I think.
是旧朋友
她可不是我的好朋友
Yeah, but I wouldn't call her such a good friend.
请她来吃饭嘛
来往多了就会成为好朋友
Invite her for dinner and you may become good friends.
就算不成 也可以让里昂摸摸她的小手
If it doesn't work out, she'll help Léon out of his bag.
咱们是天生的一对
We're a good match.
我们在一起一年半了
We've been together for six months.
从来没有人找过你
Why don't you ever bring anyone home?
没有亲戚 没有朋友
No parents, no friends.
没有人
Nobody.
只爱你一个人
I only love you.
瞧 又来了
Look again
噢 正好救命
Oh, no. Rescued just in time.
喂
Hello
加斯黑了
Joséphine.
什么？
一个钟头后准备出发
What? The George V bar in one hour.
谁呀
Who's that?
是医院 说有事
Hospital. I'm on call.
冰茶
Iced tea
借个火
Do you have a light?
一小时客房服务
Downstairs at the Régina's in an hour.
别动
Don't move.
把腿叉开
Your legs apart.
加斯黑了
Joséphine.
对不起
Excuse me.
你穿上
That's for you.
我该干嘛
What do I do now?
坐下
Sit down.
早安 客房服务部
Good morning. Room service.
马上送到
We'll be right up.
现在呢
Now what happens?
你回家
You can go home.
完了
That's all?
喂
Hello
玛利
Marie
我是
我是鲍伯
Yes? It's Bob.
你好吗
还行 还行吧
How are you? I'm fine. Just fine.
我是要恭喜你
你的第一次任务成功
I just wanted to congratulate you. I'm glad your first job went so well.
谢谢
Thank you.
都安排好了吧
Is everything else going well?
都好了
Yeah, real well.
我订婚了
I'm engaged.
那太好了
That's nice.
你的路走得很顺利
I'm glad everything's working out for you.
我要走了 祝福你以后的任务也顺利成功
I have to go now. Good luck on your next assignment.
鲍伯
Bob
什么事
Yes?
我想请你到我家来吃饭
I'd like you over for dinner at my place.
我一定到
I'd be delighted.
鲍伯
Bob
是鲍伯叔叔
Right? Uncle Bob.
快进 请进吧 她还在准备
Come in. Nice tie. She's still getting ready.
好 我来拿吧
I'll give you a hand. You have your hands full.
您太客气了 真的 还有鲜花
You shouldn't have. The flowers, I mean.
噢 香槟可是好东西
Champagne suits me fine.
嗨 鲍伯
Bob
能认识你真是太好了
I'm so pleased to get to...
你是我认识玛利以后
To know you. It's...
家里来的第一个人
You are the first member of the family I've met.
我家人都是混球
The others are a pain in the butt.
我先去把酒冰上好吗
I better put it in the fridge while it's still warm.
好吃 真的很好吃
不是吹的 真是不简单啊
It's delicious, remarkable. It's so fine and light.
噢 别别 千万别总夸她
否则我日后的日子不好过
Stop with all the compliments. My head's getting way too big.
这顶多是不难吃而已
So one more little one, but that's all.
我真的很久很久没见过玛利了
I haven't seen her for a long time, and I just find her...
你看她气色多好啊
I just find her radiant.
你猜对了
本人有一股深藏含蓄的魅力
I have to give you credit. I have a subterranean charm.
这都是你的功劳
Most aren't able to see it right away.
要相处久了才会如沐春风
You could go ten years without noticing.
瞧你
There.
鲍伯 她从来不说过去
她好象没有童年一样
Tell me. You might not believe it, but I know nothing about her childhood.
麦可 你干什么
Marco, no.
给我讲一些她小时候的事
Tell me about when she was about ten.
麦可 你答应过我的
Marco, you promised.
我答应过不问你 但我问他
I promised I wouldn't ask you, not him.
你看连问都不行了
See? She won't let me ask you a single question.
我逼过你吗
Do I press you for things?
我是心甘情愿的
Never, but I wouldn't mind.
爱是没有条件的
But I love you just the same.
瞧见了 神秘女郎
Yeah, well. You see? A brick wall.
你还告状
So I've heard.
玛利
Marie
她小时候很可爱
She was so beautiful then.
那时候她才8岁
She wore pigtails when she was only eight.
老是跟在她表姐的身旁
And she always hung around with her cousin Caroline.
她梳着条辫子
And only Caroline could braid Marie's pigtail.
跟其他的人不同
No one else.
她在辫子上扎了条缎带
She always had a ribbon in her hair...
她只肯穿白色的衣服
and she only wore white dresses.
我只会在暑假碰到她
I only saw her in the summer...
整个家族在郊外的别墅度假
when the family would rent a house in the country.
数数所有表妹和邻居
Counting all the cousins and neighbors...
至少有二十几个孩子
是一群到处捣蛋的造反精
there were at least 20 kids running around getting into trouble.
玛利还有个看家本领 学青蛙叫
Marie had a very special talent...
imitating frogs.
她经常偷偷溜到池塘里
She'd sneak down to the pond whenever she could.
搞得自己满身是泥 蹲在水边呱呱的叫
一群小孩笑翻在地
She'd jump in the mud croaking until every kid fell down laughing.
然后她就一身湿的回来
She'd come back, dripping and soaking wet...
每次她都一个德行
and every time she would use the same excuse.
“一不小心而已”
"It was just an accident"...
她总是说
with that small voice she had.
她现在还很淘气
She hasn't changed much, you know.
她没告诉你我是干哪一行的
Has Marie ever told you what I do for a living?
噢 我们家的男人不能发问
I'm not allowed to ask any questions.
我是开旅行社的
I've been working as a travel agent.
没事就得绕着地球跑
It includes some nice perks here and there.
两张去威尼斯的
Two tickets for Venice.
给你们的订婚礼物
It's my engagement present.
真不知道该说什么才好
那就别说
I don't know what to say. Well, say nothing.
老式游艇
Gondola
司鼓式引擎 对不对
是木头制的
Drum-like engine, Isn't it?
Real wood.
他也听不懂
I'm talking to myself.
看这 看这
Look at me!
好了  到了
Ah, yes
来来来 帮帮忙
Ah, ah, ah
来 当心脚下
Watch your step.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这边请
This way.
不再坐船了  我都晕了
Oh, no, not more gondola.
我要游船河 游呀 游呀
More gondola, more gondola.
我是船夫...
Gondolier...
威尼斯的船夫
from Venice!
我想要你
I want you.
我渴了 我也是
I'm thirsty too. Me too.
也饿了 我也是
Hungry too. Me too.
应声虫 帮我脱裙子
Copycat. Pull off my skirt.
快点
Right away.
开始 拉
Now come on. Pull!
来拿着
Hold this up for me.
你好 我要点餐 一份帝王沙拉
一个七色拼盘
We'd like one side order of ham San Daniele, one assortment of cheese...
还有两大瓶水
我要和我的男人作爱 一会儿会汗流雨下的
and two bottles of water because we sweat like pigs when we make love.
发神经
She's crazy.
接电话的他是不是吓坏了
What did they have to say?
他说他也会汗如雨下的
They should have the same problem at home.
这度假真好
It's good to be here.
你别怕
Don't budge.
喂
Hello
加斯黑了
Joséphine.
喂
Hello
加斯黑了
Joséphine.
我是
Yeah.
浴室的柜子里有一个暗盒
There's a secret compartment in the bathroom cabinet.
好吧 那就换甜圆沙拉好了
All right. Make it a green salad instead, please.
谢谢
Thank you.
帝王沙拉卖完了
There is no more San Daniele.
叫他们经理来
Get me the manager.
我洗个澡
I'm gonna pour a bath.
放松一下 送餐的马上就来了
Just relax and take care of room service.
加斯黑了就位了
Joséphine in position.
工具在洗脸盆下面
The first elements are under the sink.
组合完毕
Assembly complete.
打开窗子
Open the window.
你叫我怎么打开窗户
自己想办法
How am I supposed to open the window? You'll work it out.
玛利
Sweetheart?
干嘛
What?
你猜我在想什么
You know what I'm thinking?
不知道
No.
第一次在商店遇见你的时候
Of the moment I first saw you in the store. You were so beautiful.
我还以为老天是很残酷的呢
I thought, "Life can play such dirty tricks...
这么美丽的女人怎么可能共度一生呢
because I'll never have a girl like that to share my life.
跟我这个无名小卒
To be with me.
不可能的
Never."
可是我们现在却真的在一起了
Now we are both here. Together.
准备好了
Okay
运河边有一艘游艇
There's a white boat on the canal...
穿兰色衬衫
with a driver in a blue shirt.
左边有两个人在屋门口等着
To the left, there are two people waiting outside a door.
你要瞄准好
Take aim and be ready.
我们再等待进一步的命令
We're waiting for orders.
玛利
Marie
什么
我有话跟你说
Yeah? Can we talk?
说吧 不准进来
Okay, but don't come in.
玛利
Marie
我不想惹你烦 但是
I don't want to bother you with my questions.
我不知道你以前
I don't know...
发生过什么事或闯了什么祸
what you did or what happened that got you to this point...
使你变成现在这个样子
so wound up.
但是我总想着你 有时总往坏处想
But I think about it once in a while, you know?
And I imagine the worst.
可想到头了也就算了
The worst would be a relief.
谁呀
送餐的
What is it? Room service.
来了
Coming.
停在这里好了 不是卖完了吗
Stop, stop. I thought you were out of ham.
算了 放这吧 谢谢
Never mind. No big deal.
几个目标
一个 要开两枪
How many targets? Only one, but two shots.
怎么识别
还在等情报
How do I single him out? I don't have that information yet.
准备  目标十秒钟出现
Stand by. Target will be visible in ten seconds.
到底是哪一个
还在等情报
Which one is he? I don't have that information yet.
玛利
Marie
妈的 哪一个
女的
Which one, damn it? The woman.
穿咖啡色的 女的
The woman in brown.
就是那个女人 快开枪
The woman, damn it!
你在干什么 快开枪
What are you doing? The woman!
你怎么了  为什么不出声
What's wrong? Why don't you answer?
说过不准进来的
You promised not to come in.
我知道 可我听到点动静
I know, but I heard some noise.
我在门外叫你老半天
Damn it, for half an hour I've been talking from behind the door.
你怎么不出声呢
You might answer me.
行了 你一个字也没有听进去
You didn't hear a word?
好吧
All right.
路上吃
Here. For the road.
小姐
Miss?
巧克力 谢谢
Chocolate. Thank you.
你想说假期愉快是吗
Want to know how I spent my vacation, is that it?
我越来越了解你们这些虐待狂了
I'm getting to know you and your sadistic ways.
你们是一群疯子
You're mad.
用我来作工具
Totally sick.
跟着你们玩这些残忍小游戏
You just used me to play your cruel little game.
看见你真好
It's so good to see you.
还记得当你教官的时候
我真怀念那段日子
I'm guess I'm nostalgic for the times I had you all to myself.
这次是个大使
还有半年他就要任满回国了
It's an ambassador. In six months, he returns home.
必须在他回国以前完成
你可以选人手组合班子
You have to get him before he leaves. It's your show. Choose your team.
你有6个月时间 上级要求做得漂亮
You have six months. They want a nice, clean job.
我推荐了你
I thought of you.
甜言蜜语下毒手 你的老招了
You're always combining two things at once.
谁要我想念你
The vagaries of love.
不喜欢我送的花
Not impressed with your new plant?
你瞧瞧这个如何
There we are. That's much better.
从今天开始 我不再是收银员了
No more Mr. Cashier because after today, I'm finished.
我辞职了
造游艇？
I quit. You'll make boats?
对 得庆祝一下
You bet I will. Let's celebrate.
那当然
But of course.
谁教你这么笑的
Who taught you how to smile like that?
是你
You did.
咱们搬家吧
I think we should move.
我想你需要一个大一点的地方
I believe that something more spacious would suit you better.
他跟情妇在9号屋里
He went into number nine to see one of his mistresses.
一般会呆两个钟头
It'll be about a two-hour wait.
你有火吗
You have a light?
对不起 耽搁了
See you later.
给 回头见
Sorry, I got held up.
他叫杰瑞 派驻巴黎7年了
Maximilien Jedreck. Stationed in Paris for seven years.
到处搜集情报
He acquires information from all parties...
都藏在大使馆保险箱里
他打算亲自带回去
keeps it in a safe at the embassy until he can take it home with him.
保守的手法
Classic.
什么样的情报
无所不有
What kind of information? All kinds.
政治 高新科技 商业
Governmental, scientific, corporate.
女的是谁
Who's the girl?
玛瑞 搞在一起两年了
Anne-Marie something or other. They've dated about two years.
艺术经纪人 是卖油画的 似乎是清白的
She sells paintings. Apparently, she's clean.
其实我们对大使没有兴趣
In fact, we're not really interested in him.
我们想知道的是那些企业和个人出卖的国家机密
What we really want is to get the companies that are selling him the data.
他的情报就是证据
To get them, we need proof.
证据在大使馆的保险箱里
And all that proof's in the embassy safe, right?
对 钥匙一直带在他身上
目标确认就好
Yeah, and the keys are in his pocket. At least we know where to look.
两国关系很敏感
不能出错
Right now, relations with the embassy are rather strained, so go easy.
这个比杀人难多了
You can't hurt the ambassador.
只能用巧工夫 不能动武
It should be a finesse job, not a tour de force.
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
玛利
Marie
你吓死我了
You shouldn't scare me like that.
医院的护士是不是有一身药味 小姐
How can you work at a hospital and still smell so damn good?
我喜欢用香水
Strong perfume.
你好象连上三个月夜班了
如果我没记错
You've worked midnights for three months but you tell me nothing about it.
今天是最后一天
Tonight it's over.
比我所想象的还忙
It's much more work than I thought.
她说你可能会在这
She told me you might be here.
玛瑞她没有跟你说吗
Marie-Hélène. Didn't she tell you?
她没说
No, she didn't.
坐一下就走
I'll just be two minutes.
你看怎么样
Well, what do you think of it?
还行
It's okay.
让我拎到五楼来可得多给点服务费
Carrying it up five stories will make a painting worth twice as much.
你喝点什么
What can I get you to drink?
威士忌
Some whiskey.
你跟玛瑞工作多久了
You have worked with Anne-Marie how long?
我老爸的画廊跟她是邻居
Every now and then. My father owns a gallery near hers.
在同一条街上？
On the same avenue?
对 只差一个街口
Yeah, but up a block.
差一个街口
Up a block, up a block.
我想起来了 一定是那家
Ah, of course.
谢谢
Many thanks.
是芬兰画廊北边那一家
It's up just past the gallery of Finland.
真去过
Ah, you've been there.
喝光
Drink it.
咕噜 咕噜
Glug, glug.
躺下好好睡一觉
Now down on the couch. You're gonna sleep a little.
克里斯汀 有个清洁女工要上楼
Christian, it's just a cleaning lady on her way up.
好 知道了
Okay, I've got it.
加斯黑了
Joséphine
是
Yeah?
大使馆有暗语口令
The ambassador uses a password with his guards.
我知道口令
口令已经改了
But we know the password. They changed it this morning.
我们的情报证实
We just got word from surveillance.
行动得取消了 是吗
等一下 我查查看
So we have to call it off? Hold on. I'll find out.
不变 任务继续
怎么继续
No, the mission is maintained. How do I do that?
等着 我们派个清理工过来
Wait there. We're sending in a cleanup man.
这是我的案子 我已经耗了半年
Look, it's my mission. For six months...
闭嘴 紧急通知
Shut up. Orders are orders.
这个案子改为最高级
明白了没有
The mission is maintained with maximum priority. Understand?
去你妈的烂清理工
You can shove your stinking cleanup man!
太危险了 我看咱们还是撤吧
It's not safe. Shouldn't we go?
等等 一会跟来的人谈谈
No, let's talk to the man.
莫里斯
Maurice?
莫里斯 谁上来了
Maurice, who's coming up?
我没事 你给我冷静
I'm fine. Keep calm.
我没事
I'm fine!
我去开门
I'll get it.
我是威可多 清理工
Victor, the cleaner.
浴室在哪儿
在那 在那边
Where's the bathroom? Over there.
把大使也拖进来
Bring me the guy on the couch.
司机呢
后备箱里
And the chauffeur? In the trunk.
人来了 你得跟他们谈呀 笨蛋
Talk to the man. He's right there! You stupid idiot!
活得不耐烦了  想跟他们一样？
You want to end up dead too?
威可多 现在什么计划
Victor, we've got to make a plan.
没有计划
No plans.
那是什么玩意
What is that stuff for, then?
救命的玩意
To save your ass.
混蛋 怎么他还是活的 怎么回事
You bastards! I thought you'd killed him.
你简直是疯了
快帮我压住他
You're an absolute maniac! Hold him down!
我干不了了 拿去
I'm through! Get over here.
拿去吧 拿去
Take this, and this! It's over!
疯子
先把他解决掉
Shut the fuck up. Finish him off.
大使馆你自己也能去 把钥匙也拿去吧
You can go to the embassy yourself! Here! Take the keys!
先把他解决掉 先把他解决掉
Finish him off! I'll finish him off!
威可多
Victor
我们打电话请示上级行吗
Maybe I should call them for further instructions.
不 威可多
Victor, no, no, Victor
我执行任务从不半途而废
I am not about to stop this mission.
不准打电话
There will be no phone calls.
不跟我去执行任务
就跟他们进洗澡缸
We'll finish this mission, or you're going with the others. Is that clear?
跟你一起进去吧
不
Maybe I should come with you. You'd better not.
你在车上等着
只要给我一个小时就够了 好吗
Just stay here. I'll be one hour.
你冷静点 别冲动
And please calm down. Calm down.
就给你一个小时
Fine, but only an hour.
威可多
Victor
怎么可能这么快
You can't be done.
得完成任务
I'm finishing this off now.
我已经拍到资料了
We've got what we needed to get.
只要能带我出去就算完成任务了
If we can drive out, that's all.
快走啊
All right?
我得进去看看
Let's finish the mission.
求求你了 威可多
没时间了
No, please. Victor, Time's up.
快走吧 别逞强了
Let's go home. Please.
那个家伙是谁
不知道
And who is this guy? It doesn't matter.
大使先生没事吧
Ambassador, is there something wrong?
噢 天啊
My God.
快跑
Let's get out!
马上警戒 搜索
The guards are in place.
没事 没事 警报器坏了 妈的
It's nothing. It's a false alarm. Stay calm.
威可多
Victor
铁门关了 我们出不去了
They've shut the gate. We'll be trapped in here.
我还得回来
We'll be back.
站住
Halt!
绕两圈再杀回来
小心
Around the block, then right back. They'll kill us!
挪一下
Move over.
转过来好吗
Look at me, Marie.
我可怜的宝贝
My poor, dear Marie.
不能再干了
They've worn you out.
这行饭不是你能吃的
太残忍
This job isn't for you. It's too hard.
你该停手了
It's time to stop it.
我只想跟你在一起
You mean so much to me.
这是我人生意义的全部
And I want to take care of you.
没有任何事情值得去冒险
Life together is too valuable for us to risk.
你在说什么
Why are you saying this?
我都知道了
It's the truth.
医院说没你这个人
There's no Marie Clément at the hospital.
你的经历我都清楚了
I know what's going on.
你干的那些跟踪
How much you go through.
特务 谋杀
The spying, the surveillance...
这都是证明
the videotapes.
你怎么没说过
Why haven't you said anything?
因为我爱你
I only love you.
谢谢你 谢谢 谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
你是我唯一的爱人 麦可
My sweet Marco.
我真的感觉到这唯一的爱
The world has given me only this one taste of love.
我会永远记得你
And I will remember you always.
你 你要离开我
You're leaving tonight?
我们一起逃吧
Maybe you'll let me come too.
我们是不同世界的人
I want you to stay.
我爱你
I love you.
马蒂欧 我先上去
Mathieu, I'll go first.
有问题再呼你们
I'll call if there's a problem.
怎么没带花
What no flowers this time?
没有
No
到什么时候才算完
For how long has she...
她欠你们的债
Hasn't she paid her debt?
她就不能选择自己的生活吗
Can't she have her own life anymore?
你毁了她
我救了她
You destroyed her life. I know what I've done.
她当年也谋杀了一个生命
But you should know that she also destroyed a life.
一个警察的生命
A cop's life.
让人无法忘记
And that's too hard to forget.
那她要杀多少来还债
She killed how many for you?
你不数数人头
Why does it only count when it suits you?
好了 麦可
Okey, Marco
如果你真的都知道
Maybe you do understand the situation.
好了 你知道我们当初是怎么救她的
Fine, then. I'll listen. Ask yourself how we save her.
这次还能救吗
Can't you protect her?
我也想
I'll try...
可是她逼着我们追捕她
but she's forced me to hunt her.
我们一定要找回资料
Because we must have all the embassy documents.
那你可以放过她了 底片在我这
Her troubles are over, then, because I have them with me here.
她留了字条 可是我撕了
She left a note for you with it, but I tore it up.
上面说什么
What did it say?
我们都会想她
I think we'll miss her.
是
Yeah.